kemba.org 2011-10-08

# KEMBA: Privacy Notice

Quick Fact

********Financial institutions have federal, state and local guidelines they must follow regarding the use of electronic funds transfers and are required to give you a copy of this information when an account is opened. Once they have complied, it then becomes _your responsibility_ to review and understand your rights and the privileges of carrying an ATM, DEBIT or CREDIT CARD.  
********

| 

Our Privacy Notice is an important part of our commitment to provide you with the best financial and client service possible. We believe it is essential to clarify how KEMBA uses collected information, the benefits of such use and the way information is protected against unauthorized access and use. Your concern about the security of information relating to you and your accounts is understandable and we want to assure you that we are continuously taking steps to safeguard your personal information. It is also essential that you know that we do not sell customer lists or individual customer information to any third parties.

Each member relationship at KEMBA is built on trust. We have implemented policies, procedures and controls to help safeguard and prevent unauthorized disclosure of non-public personal information, as well as detect any such unauthorized disclosures. KEMBA employees are trained to handle member matters and maintain confidence in a manner consistent with applicable laws and this notice. In addition, only employees actively engaged in the discharge of assigned duties involving customer information are authorized to access that information. 

KEMBA Financial Credit Union has taken reasonable measures to ensure that the information and data presented on this website is accurate, appropriate and up to date. While every effort is made to maintain the accuracy and utility of this information, KEMBA makes no express or implied warranty regarding such information or data, and hereby disclaims all legal liability and responsibility to persons or entities that use or access this site and its content, based on their reliance on any information or data obtained through this website. 

Information on this website is not intended to constitute and should not be considered as legal or financial advice, nor is it intended to substitute for obtaining legal or financial advice from competent, appropriate and independent legal counsel or financial advisor. This website content is not designed or intended to provide authoritative financial, accounting, investment or other professional financial advice which may be reasonably relied on by its readers. If expert assistance in this area is required, the services of a qualified professional should be retained. 

## Links to Other Websites

This KEMBA website provides links to other websites for convenience and informational purposes only. Users should be aware that when you select a link on the KEMBA website to an external website, you are leaving the KEMBA site. You will see a disclosure on our site that alerts you when you are leaving our website. Linked sites are not under the control of KEMBA, and KEMBA is not responsible for the contents of any linked site or any link contained in a linked site, or changes or updates to such sites. Inclusion of such links in the KEMBA website does not imply endorsement by KEMBA of the site, its content, advertisers or sponsors. For your protection, we recommend that you review the separate privacy notices provided on these linked websites. External sites may contain copyrighted materials with restrictions on use and reuse, whereby permission for use or reuse must be obtained from the original source, not from KEMBA. 

## Use of “Cookies” on this Website to Collect Data

KEMBA financial Credit Union is strongly committed to protecting and maintaining the privacy of your non-public, personal information. Our information gathering and dissemination practices for this site are described as follows. KEMBA automatically collects and stores the following information when you visit our website:  

  * Date and time your request was received
  * Your Internet Protocol (IP) address, or the address of your Internet Service Provider (ISP)
  * Specific resource on KEMBA website that was accessed as a result of the request or application
  * Content of any sent or received cookie *

(* Some parts of the KEMBA website may use a “cookie,” which is a file placed on your computer hard drive that allows the KEMBA server to log the pages you use in the KEMBA website to determine if you have visited the site before. It also stores your preferences and other information on your computer to save you time by eliminating the need to repeatedly enter the same information and to display your personalized content. No personal identifying information is captured by the cookie. This information is used by the KEMBA server to provide certain website features during your visit. You can set your browser to warn you when placement of a cookie is requested, and decide whether or not to accept it. By rejecting a cookie, some of the features available on the site may not function properly.)

Other than the automatic data collection activity described above, this site collects no personally identifiable information. When you knowingly and voluntarily provide personal, non-public information, such as when you complete data fields on a loan application, you have chosen to make an exception to the automatic data collection as described. 

## Information We Share

We may share public and non-public personal information concerning your transactions and experience within KEMBA and related organizations. This sharing of information is intended to help us offer financial products and services we believe would benefit you and facilitate the servicing of your accounts. You have a choice as to whether or not you want this information shared with KEMBA-related organizations. If you prefer that we not share this information, you may opt out by writing to us at KEMBA Financial Credit Union, Attention: Compliance Officer, 555 Officenter Place, P.O. Box 307370, Gahanna, Ohio 43230. Please provide your name, address and account number(s). 

Other non-public personal information may be shared with service providers who assist us in servicing your accounts and preparing and/or delivering financial services and products to you on our behalf. Examples of such third-party service providers include check printers, data processors, deposit or loan account service providers, check verification services, and credit reporting agencies.   

Information we collect, as described above, may also be shared with companies that perform marketing services on our behalf or with other financial institutions with whom we have joint marketing agreements. This allows us to offer a variety of financial products and services we endorse and believe you may find beneficial. These companies we do business with agree to keep such information confidential and are prohibited from disclosing such information to anyone for any other purpose. We do not, and will not, share your information with non-financial companies for the purpose of allowing them to market their products and services to you.   

KEMBA does not disclose any non-public personal information about you to any other third parties except as permitted or required by law. We do not share medical or health insurance information, nor will we disclose medical information to unaffiliated third parties unless you have instructed us to do so in writing.   

Information about KEMBA member accounts may be reported to credit bureaus. Late payments, missed payments, or other defaults on your accounts may be reflected in your credit report. 

## Email Communications

When you choose to identify yourself to KEMBA and provide an email address as an accepted communication channel, you are consenting to KEMBA using the information you provide, including personally identifying information, in accordance with this notice, unless you expressly state in the email your objection to any use(s). This may include the transmission of service communications such as welcome letters, billing reminders, technical service information and security announcements. Since general email is not secure and may be intercepted or viewed by others, you should refrain from sending confidential or private information via email.   

## Information Security Standards

KEMBA Financial Credit Union continually updates and improves our security standards and procedures to help protect against anyone gaining unauthorized access to your confidential information and to prevent fraud. We maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards that comply with federal standards. Our associates have an appropriate level of access to your personal information in order to perform their jobs and provide you with the best financial products and services possible. We do work with law enforcement officials to pursue any individuals who either fraudulently access or attempt to access or use information. We are continually looking for new technology to further enhance the security of this information. Through appropriate checks and balances built into procedures—such as asking you for information only you would know—we work to properly identify you when you contact us. 

Information provided via this website is submitted in a secure session utilizing Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology to ensure that the information is encrypted. If a password is used to help protect your accounts and personal information, it is your responsibility to keep your password confidential and protected. Do not share your password with anyone. If you are sharing a computer, you should always log out of the site or service before leaving a terminal to prevent access to your information by a subsequent user.

## Children’s Information

Information on the KEMBA website is intended for general adult audiences, not for children. We respect the privacy of children and comply with the practices established under the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA). We do not knowingly collect or retain non-public personal information from anyone under the age of eighteen unless that information is provided to us by an adult authorized to do so. If you are under 18 years of age, you should only access this website with the involvement of a parent or guardian.

These privacy guidelines have been developed with the recognition that Internet technologies are rapidly evolving, and that underlying business models and procedures are constantly being challenged and modified. Accordingly, this notice is subject to change. Any such changes will be posted on this page as appropriate.

**Search the Website**
